嘿，大家好，我是TheCherno，欢迎回到我的游戏引擎系列
hey, what's up guys, my name is TheCherno, welcome back to my game engine series
所以在过去几周里，生活像往常一样忙碌，对于那些不知道的人来说，我两周后就要结婚了
so over the last few weeks, of course my life has been hectic as always and getting married in two weeks for those of you who don't know
我真的很高兴能坐下来，有时间再花点时间在Hazel上
I'm really excited to just sit down, and have some time to spend on Hazel once again
我迫不及待地想等我生活中发生的一切都结束了
and I can't wait for all of this stuff is going on in my life to kind of just be over
这样我就可以重新过上正常的平静生活了，但不管怎样，还是让我们继续说说Hazel吧
so that I can just kind of get back to just having a normal peaceful life, but anyway anyway let's just kind of move on and talk about Hazel
因为我在这期之前所做的一切都是完全没有计划的，这一切都不是有计划的
because what I did before this episode is like this is completely unplanned, none of this is planned
我大概知道我要做什么，只是因为我已经考虑过了，但没有任何计划
I know roughly what I'm going to do just because I've thought about it, but there's nothing's planned
所以我们要做期精彩的现场直播，因为你们似乎很喜欢，似乎不喜欢我计划事情的时候
so we're just going to have a nice live episode, because you guys seem to love that, you guys seem to not like when I plan things
然后只是复制一些代码，我甚至不知道今天需要写什么代码
and then just copy and base some code, I actually don't even know what code I want to write today
我们只是想看看进展如何，说一些事情
we're just gonna kind of see how we go, we're gonna talk about some stuff
这几乎很像cherno之前的视频风格
it's almost gonna be like a good old fashioned kind of cherno episode
像往常一样，我想做的第一件事就是感谢让这一切成为可能的人
first thing I want to do as always is just thank the people who make this possible
patreon.com/thecherno是你们支持我的一种方式，确保我可以继续创作这些视频
patreon.com/thecherno is a way for you guys to support me, and make sure that I can keep making these videos
尤其是在这样的时候，对所有让这一切成为可能的人来说，这是一件大事
especially in time like this a huge thing here to everyone who's making this stuff possible
今天我们将讨论Hazel的情况，我们将从渲染器开始，以及整个渲染器方面
today we're gonna just talk about what is going on with Hazel, we're gonna start on the renderer, and the whole renderer side of things
我们就那样讨论，在Hazel架构中有很多东西，我已经忽视了一段时间了
and we're just gonna talk about like that, there's a bunch of things going on in Hazel architecturally that I have kind of been ignoring for a while
事实上，我甚至不能百分之百确定是否真的会建立一个干净的仓库，所以还有很多事情要做
and in fact I'm even not 100% sure that a clean check out of the depository actually will build, so there's just a lot of things going on
但今天它将讨论很多事情，这将是一个什么样的方向，以及如何开始渲染器
but it's going to kind of talk about a lot of things today, and where this is going to kind of go as well as get a start on the renderer
因此这期视频的标题可能类似于你们知道的，渲染OpenGL，渲染上下文和交换通道之类的
so this video will probably be titled something like you know, rendering OpenGL, rendering context and swap channel something like that
我不知道，但我们也会讨论一些事情，所以第一步是看看所有事情的状态
I don't know, but we'll kind of just talk about things as well, so first step is to take a look at the state of everything
那么让我们继续看一下我打开Hazel时看到的内容，好吧
so let's just go ahead and take a look at what I saw when I opened Hazel, alright
所以我想我实际上做了什么，在某种意义上我忘记了什么，如果我们看看这个错误列表
so I think what I actually did and what I kind of forgot about in a sense, if we just take a look at this error list
我刚刚做了一个干净的构建，我想到了一切，我们有这个，所以有很多警告，三个链接错误
I just did a clean build, I think of everything and we have this, so we have a lot of warnings, and we have three linking errors
因为我实际上完全忘记了，所以我继续描述渲染器，并介绍了渲染视频
because I actually completely forgot, I went on to describing the renderer with the introduction to rendering video
以及渲染接口架构视频
as well as the actual kind of rendering api architecture video
但在此之前，我问了你们一个问题，我们如何解决这些问题
but before that what I did was I actually gave you guys a question as to how do we fix these
我们这里的ImGui链接错误，对吧，然后我展示给大家，让大家完全忘记那些东西
ImGui linking errors that we have over here, right, and then I presented to completely forget about that stuff
因为我现在的生活当然是一团糟，但无论如何，不是那样，这是一团糟，但只是
because of course my life is just huge mess right now, but anyway, not that, it's a bad mess but it's just
只是很难做很多事情，不管怎样都要解决，所以我们有这样的链接错误
it's just it's very hard to do a lot of things, that want settle anyway, so we have these kind of linking errors
我问你们为什么会有它们，因为实际上发生了什么
and I asked you guys why we having them, because essentially what's happening
我向你们提出了一个问题，我们如何解决这个问题，这里发生的是
and I gave you guys the question of how do we fix this stuff, what's happening here is that
如果我们看看这里所有这些模块的架构，就会发现
if we look at kind of the just the build architecture of all these modules that we have here, what's happening is
ImGui是作为一个静态库构建的，对吧，如果我们转到这里的属性
ImGui is being built as a static library, right, if we just go to properties over here
我们来看看这个配置类型在哪里，它当然是一个静态库，我们在premake中做了那个
and we take a look at where are we this this configuration type, it's such a static library of course, and we did that in premake
那意味着它是静态构建的，对吧，所以我们用所有ImGui代码构建一个静态库
what that means is that it's building statically, right, so we're building a static library out of all of the ImGui code
很好，对吧，但接下来发生的事情被链接到Hazel，Hazel是一个dll文件，对吧
which is great, right, but then what's happening is being linked into Hazel, Hazel is a dll file, right
这意味着链接实际上发生了，对吧，dll文件与exe文件非常相似，因为它们只是
which means that linking actually occurs, right, dll files are very much like exe files in the sense that they just kind of
它们有相似的入口点和所有这些，但在这个意义上，它们将实际的库链接到
well they have like entry points and all of that, but in this sense, they link the actual the actual library into
就像库实际上被链接到这个dll文件中一样，所有的事情都必须在链接时解决，对吧，那很好
like libraries actually get linked into this dll file, and everything has to be resolved at link time, right, so that's great
因为这意味着Hazel中ImGui的任何使用都将在链接或链接所有函数中得到解决，那很好
because it means that any usage of ImGui inside Hazel will just be resolved in the link or link all the functions, and that's great
但问题来自Sandbox，当决定在Sandbox中实际使用ImGui函数时，只需链接我们链接的内容
but the issue comes from Sandbox, when we decide to actually hmm use ImGui functions in Sandbox by just linking what we link which is
实际上，它甚至不是这个东西
well it's actually not even this stuff
它是在额外的依赖关系中，我们实际上已经链接到链接器中的东西
that's in the additional dependencies is just stuff that we've actually linked into the linker
在本例中，它与C++标准库类似，也与Visual Studio类似于microsoft windows类库
which in this case, is just like C++ standard library libraries, and also Visual Studio kind of like microsoft windows kind of libraries
你们知道，就像kernel32之类的库，但如果我们看引用，你们可以看到引用了Hazel
you know, like kernel32 and use the 32 that kind of stuff, but if we look at references, you can see references Hazel
那就是链接所发生的，所以Sandbox是一个可执行文件，它链接这个Hazel.dll文件
that's what the linking is happening, so Sandbox is an exe, that links this Hazel.dll file
问题是如果我们在Sandbox中使用ImGui的Begin和End，对吧，但在Hazel中并没有使用
problem is if we use something like ImGui Begin and End inside Sandbox, right, however that hasn't been used inside Hazel
猜猜当Hazel链接ImGui时会发生什么，它不会去链接那些符号
well guess what happens when Hazel links ImGui, it does not link those symbols
对吧，因为为什么没有使用它们，对吧，所以它们崩了
right, because why because they're not used, right, so they're dead
为什么它们在这个二进制文件中包含这些函数，如果它们不被使用，它就不会执行那个
why on earth were they include those functions in this binary, if they're not used, it doesn't do that
但正因为如此，这意味着它们没有暴露在Sandbox中，那么如何解决这个问题呢
but because of that, it means that they're not exposed to Sandbox, so what is the way of fixing this
我们有几种方法可以解决这个问题，对吧，有一种方法就是看看ImGui::Begin
well there's several ways we could fix this, right, we could like one way literally is just like oh look ImGui::Begin
如果来到Hazel/ImGui，抱歉不是vendor，是Hazel/src，你们知道ImGuiLayer或其他什么
well you know if we were to go into Hazel ImGui, sorry not vendor, Hazel src, you know ImGuiLayer or whatever
并且我也不知道，那就直接用ImGui::Begin()和ImGui::End()吧
and I don't know just use like Begin, let's just use Begin and End
对吧，如果我再构建一次所有这些东西，好吧，因此那就无法运行了
right, if I do a build again of all of this stuff, okay, so that didn't work
那可能是因为我认为任何ImGui符号都不会以这种速度导出，IMGUI_API正是我们所需要的
and that's probably because I don't think any ImGui symbols are actually being exported at this rate, IMGUI_API is kind of what we need
那可能根本设置不正确，我不知道这是否值得探索，因为这只是一个临时解决方案
and that's probably not set correctly at all, I don't know if it's worth exploring this, because it's just a temporary solution
但如果我们看看Hazel/vendor/ImGui，然后看看premake文件，我想我们会发现
but if we take a look at perhaps Hazel/vendor/ImGui, and then the premake file, I think we'll find that
好像它根本没有定义，而我们可能应该定义IMGUI_API，应该是
yeah like it's not defined at all, whereas we should probably define ImGui, the IMGUI_API here to be
让我来看看，例如，应该定义IMGUI_API来处理所有导出
let me just find something, and for example IMGUI_API should probably be defined to deal all export
所以让我们继续，我真的不想做这个，但我会很快实现这个来证明我的观点
so let's go ahead and again I don't really want to do this, but I'll do this just quickly to demonstrate my point
因此把ImGui_API定义为空，事实上，让我们这样做，只是因为它不仅仅是期演示视频
so let's define ImGui_API as no one, in fact let's just do it in this,  just because it is a, just because it is not just a demo video
因此，我们将ImGui_API定义为__declspec(dllexport)，我们将构建ImGui和Hazel，对吧
so we'll define ImGui_API to be __declspec(dllexport), we will build ImGui and Hazel, right
然后我们要做的是去掉__declspec(dllexport)，它实际上触发了重建
and then what we'll do is we'll take away that __declspec(dllexport), which actually my trigger a rebuild
现在我想我可能真的很蠢，是的，的确如此，没关系，那行不通，所以不如做得更好一点
now that I think about I'm probably really stupid, yes it did, never mind, that's not gonna work, so instead how about we do it a bit better
在ImGui中构建功能，我们实际上包含了这些东西，但实际上并没有包含所有内容
and inside the ImGui to build functional, we actually include this stuff, which we don't actually include everything
不管怎样，这是没有办法的，让我们好好做吧，我本来打算通过黑客破解
anyway, there's no really way around this, let's just do it properly, I was going to hack my way through this
但很明显那不太好，所以我很快要做的是，对于Hazel
but clearly that's just not great, so what I'll do quickly here is for Hazel
在预处理器内部，我将把IMGUI_API设置为__declspec(dllexport)，好了
inside the preprocessor, I'll just set IMGUI_API equal to __declspec(dllexport) like that, all right
然后在ImGui中，我想我也会这样做
and then inside ImGui, I guess I'll do the same
然后在Sandbox中，我会将其设置为dllimport，对吧，这只是一个小小的快速破解
and then inside Sandbox, I'll set it to import, right, this is just a little quick hack
希望现在这个能解决这些符号，因为它们已经被使用了，让我们看看，好了
and then hopefully this now should actually resolve those symbols, because they've been used, so let's take a look at that, okay
所以我们在这里得到了一个成功的构建，对吧，或者那已经解决了
so we get a we get a successful build here, right, or that's kind of been resolved
所以那就是你们能做的，可以把它向前推进
so that's what you can do, you can just kind of forward that
但问题是，如果我们实际上不使用符号，对吧，所以我不知道，我会尝试删除这个
but again the problem is that, if we don't actually use the symbols, right, so I don't know I'll try and remove this
我不确定它在这种情况下是否可行，这取决于它们以前是否被使用过
I'm not sure if it like it might work in this situation, it depends if they've been used before like yeah so that built
但如果我们尝试使用ImGui::，你们知道的ColorEdit4或其他一些你们知道的函数
but if we maybe try and use something like ImGui, you know ColorEdit4 or something you know
让我们试着做一些类似的事情，只是把它黑进去
let's just try and do something like that, just to hack it in
然后可能最终不会链接，好吧，它确实链接了，很棒
then that might ultimately not link, okay, it does link, great
在这一点上，一切都是最糟糕的，一切都正常，一切正常，但不应该运行
everything's the worst at this point, everything just works, everything works, but it's not supposed to work
无论如何，我的观点是，某些符号可能无法完全转发，但那只是一个解决方案
anyway, my point again being that, certain symbols might not get completely forwarded, but that is a solution
我给你们看的是一个解决方案，你们可以确保它们在某处被实际使用
what I'm just showing you is a solution, you can just kind of make sure that they're actually used somewhere
然后根据需要执行__declspec(dllimport)导入，使用这些符号，就像我向你们展示的那样
and then do a __declspec(dllimport) as requires that you actually get to use those symbols, right, in the way that I showed you
实际上，那是完全可能的，如果我们只是这样做，我甚至不知道我们的目标是什么
that's totally possible in effect, if we just run this, I didn't even know what out goal was it
只要有一个窗口，上面写着hello world，我想，它就在那里
just to have a window that says hello world I guess, and there it is
对吧，我们可以把它拖出来，这很酷，好了
right, and we can drag it out, which is pretty cool, okay
因此我们有个漂亮窗口，这是一个解决方案，另一个解决方案，只想重申一下这个问题
so there we have that window beautiful, that is a solution, another solution, and I just want to reiterate the problem
我知道这应该是一个渲染视频，但可能会有点偏离轨道，因为这是完全没有计划的
I know this was supposed to be a rendering video, but maybe moved on a little bit off the rail, because this is completely unplanned
但无论如何，你们可以做的另一件事可能是更好的解决方案
but anyway, another thing that you could do and the board would probably be the better solution
长期而言，因为这再次依赖于我们再次遇到的问题是，ImGui将静态库构建到dll文件中
long term because again this relies the problem we have again is that, ImGui builds a static library into a dll file
但是dll文件有能力从ImGui中删除所有未使用的内容，因此如果链接dll文件的exe文件
but the dll file has the power to strip everything that's unused from ImGui, so if the exe file which links the dll file
其中有一个静态lib，如果它决定使用不存在的东西，就会出现链接错误
which has a static lib in it, if that decides to use something that is not present, there will get a linking error
理想情况下，你们要做的是确保ImGui中的所有内容都导出到dll文件中
ideally what you would do is make sure that everything from ImGui is exported into the dll file
但是，在不实际使用这些函数或确保使用它们的情况下，如何做到这一点呢
but how do you do that without actually using those functions or making sure that they are used
答案基本上是使用一个模块文件，一个模块定义文件，即def文件def，对吧
the answer is basically to use a module file, a module definition file which is the def file def, right
在这里，你们要做的是列出所有要导出的函数签名，那就是dll将导出的函数
what you do in there is you list all the function signatures that you want to export, and that is what the dll will export
如果我们快速过一下Hazel，我甚至不知道它在哪里，因为我认为这是一个输入
if we take a look at Hazel really quickly, I don't even know where this is, because I think it's an input
是了，我们有一个模块定义文件，所以我们基本上可以像Hazel.def文件一样
yeah we have a module definition file, so we can make like a Hazel def file essentially
其中列出了我们要从ImGui导出的所有函数
which has all of the functions that we want to export from ImGui listed
那意味着Hazel从ImGui中链接的所有函数都在这个定义文件中
what that means is that everything that Hazel links in from ImGui, that is inside this definition file
它实际上还将包含在二进制文件和标记导出，以便可以在Sandbox中导入它，那将解决问题
it will also actually include in our binary and marked for export, so that we can import it inside Sandbox, and that will fix the problem
不幸的是，这些def文件不容易制作，就像你们必须手动制作一样，据我所知，没有工具
unfortunately these def files are not easy to make, like you have to make them manually, as far as I know there's no tools to do them
我相信我真的有一个，如果我们快速看一看，非赞助人的小预告
and I believe I actually have one of them, if we take a look really quickly little sneak preview for non patrons
我们切到Hazel开发库，看看Hazel，你们可以看到我实际上在这里创建了一个def文件
we just jump into the Hazel dev repository, and take a look at Hazel, you can see I actually made a definition file here
所以我们有Hazel.def文件，它有ShowDemoWindow，Begin，End和ColorEdit4之类的签名
so we have a Hazel.def file, which has like ShowDemoWindow Begin and ColorEdit4 that kind of stuff, right
你们可以看到，我们有库Hazel，它导出以下选项
and you can see that we have library Hazel, and it exports the following options
那就是我们如何将它们传递到我们的Sandbox项目中，所以这很痛苦
and that's how we can actually propagate them into our Sandbox project, so this is a pain
因为你们必须获得签名，对吧，然后每次都必须手动对所有函数执行签名
because you have to get the signature, right, and then every time you have to do that for all the functions manually
所以说实话，这很糟糕，我讨厌它，这就是为什么我一直在和所有用户频道的人讨论
so it sucks, to be honest, I hate it, which is why I've kind of been having a discussion with all the people on the patron channel
这是Hazel开发频道，一直在讨论是否应该将Hazel转换为静态库
which is the Hazel dev channel, kind of been having a discussion as to maybe we should convert Hazel into a static library
因为dll文件很棒，但老实说，我也不喜欢dll文件
because dll files are great, but they also, to be honest, I don't like dll files
我最初想与Hazel达成妥协的原因可能是因为可能存在热更新代码
the reason I wanted to make Hazel a deal originally is because of maybe the possibility of hot swapping code
而且也只是为了让客户端的链接更容易
and and also just to make a client side kind of linking easier
这意味着如果我们用Hazel做一个游戏，在这种情况下是Sandbox，对吧
meaning that if we make a game with Hazel, which in this case is Sandbox, right
唯一需要链接的是Hazel，因为Hazel是个dll，其中包含所有其他内容，那显然有好处
the only thing we have to link is Hazel, because Hazel is a dll file, which contains everything else, that has a benefit obviously
但它也有缺点，首先，这个好处很容易修复，因为我们使用的是premake构建系统
but it also has the drawback, well first of all, that benefit is easily fixed, because we're using premake sr build systems
所以我们没有理由不能生成一个游戏类的premake文件，它实际上链接了所有需要的东西
so there's no reason why we can't generate a game kind of premake file, which actually links everything that's needed anyway
在我看来，无论何时我要用Hazel制作一个游戏
and in my opinion, whenever I'd be work making a game with Hazel
我都希望有一个VS解决方案，其中包含所有内容，对吧
I would want a visual studio solution with everything in it anyway, right
所以事实上，我们只需要将一件事与游戏联系起来并没有什么大不了的
so the fact that we only have to link one thing into the game isn't actually that big of a deal
因为同样，每次我们创建一个新项目时，我们都会设置好premake文件，它会显示所有内容
because again, we'll have the premake file already set up, every time we create a new project, which looks everything
不管怎样，静态库的好处当然是，所有内容都链接到我构建的exe文件中
anyway, benefits of static libraries of course are essentially that, everything just gets linked into that exe file I built time
这意味着一切都是正确的版本，一切都是最新的，C++标准库，我们有一个版本
which means everything is kind of the right version, everything's up to date, the C++ standard library, we have one version of that
我们不需要像现在这样动态链接，静态链接有速度优势，对吧，这意味着
which we do not need to dynamically link like we are right now, there's speed benefits for static linking right meaning that
因为链接器知道所有输入的符号，所以它实际上可以进行诸如内联之类的优化
because the linker is aware of all the symbols coming in, it can actually do optimizations like inlining
这对于dll文件是不可能的，因为它是一个单独的模块，我们也有好处
which is impossible with the dll file, because it's a separate module, we also have benefits
比如我们不需要动态链接库文件，我们只有一个exe文件
such as what we don't need dll files floating around, we just have one exe file
那就是我们的整个游戏，就是那样，没有动态链接库
and that's our entire game, that's it, no dlls
这是我脑子里想不到的，我们不需要愚蠢的导出输入宏，如果我们看看有多少警告
what else is this just off the top of my head, we don't need stupid export input macros, and like if we look at just how many warnings we have
在我说话的时候，会做个快速重建，如果我们看看所有这些警告，其中一半真的很烦人
I'll just do a quick rebuild while I'm talking, if we have a look at all these warnings we have, half of them are just really annoying
因为dll的边界，就像这个例子，所以停在这里，你们知道，我错过了它，它在哪里
and because of dll boundaries, you know like this for example, so kind of stop this here, you know, and I missed it where is it
你们知道这个shared_ptr需要有dll接口才能供客户端使用，那是一个非常恼人的错误
you know this shared_ptr needs to have dll interface to be used by clients, that's a really annoying error
这基本上是无法修复的，因为我们正在跨dll边界使用shared_ptr，对吧
which you basically can't really fix, because we're using shared_ptr across dll boundaries, right
那真的很烦人，模板有时也会受到影响，所以有很多非常重要的
that's really annoying templates also sometimes suffer, so there's a lot of like really important
我的意思是，我们通过dll遇到了很多非常恼人的错误，老实说，我现在的方式是
I mean a lot of really annoying errors that we have via dll, so to be honest, at the way I'm landing right now is
我可能只是想用预热来处理它，这是我很久以来一直在做的事了
I might just want to nuke this and just go with, it's a time man I've been doing so long
我可能总是想取消它并使用静态库，对吧，那是一种想法
I might always want to nuke that and go with static libraries, right, that's kind of the idea
所以我想那就是我要做的，让我知道你们对在评论中将Hazel转换为静态库的想法
so I think that that's what I'll do, let me know what your thoughts are regarding converting Hazel to a static library in the comments
很明显，两者都可以支持，因此如果你们想将其构建为dll，你们可以
there is obviously the possibility of supporting both, so if you want to build it as a dll, you can
如果你们想构建一个静态库，你们可以，我想得越多，对支持这两种方式的兴趣就越小
if you want to build a static library, you can, the more I think about it than less interest I have in supporting both ways
我相信，尤其是对于像Hazel这样的项目，它主要是由我一个人完成的，对吧，支持太多了
I believe that especially for a project like Hazel, which has worked on primarily by just me, right, supporting too much
支持一个非常灵活的构建风格或工作流将是一个很难维护的问题，我认为这并不健康
and supporting a very flexible build style or workflow is just going to be a pain to maintain, and I don't think it's healthy
我认为，对于Hazel来说，我们作为一个团队
I think that it's better for Hazel for us as a group
最好定义一组好的相似的东西来遵循Hazel，对吧，这意味着
to define a good set of like things to follow for Hazel, right, meaning that
你们知道，让我们定义在Hazel中构建游戏的方式，对吧
you know let's define the way that you build games in Hazel, right
在这种情况下，当你们使用静态库时，如何构建它们，对吧
how do you build them while you use a static library in this case, right
你们有一个实际的流水线工作流，它定义得非常好，非常健壮，然后人们就会遵循它
you kind of have an actual pipeliner workflow, that's really well defined and really robust, and then people will follow that
弹性回收就是为什么像unity和unreal一样，有时对某些特定任务来说确实不是很好的引擎
you know, this flexibility garbage is why like unity and unreal, sometimes are really not good engines for certain specific tasks
它们只是通用引擎，一切都做得很好
they're just generalist engines, which do everything really well
那很好，非常灵活，很容易使用，但我想我不想在Hazel上使用它
which is great and really flexible and easy to work with, but I don't want that in Hazel I guess
因为就像我们不能建立一个大型的通用扩展那样，意思是我没有1k人团队来处理这个问题
because like we can't build a big general extension does it, I mean I don't have a team of 1000 people working on this
对吧，我们不能构建那么大的引擎，所以我们应该做的是，我认为只是有个紧密的工作流
right, we can't build an engine that big, so what we should do, I think is just have a really tight workflow
对于一些人来说，这可能会激怒些人，但希望我们能在这里尝试定义和决定些合理的东西
which again for some people, might annoy some people, but hopefully we'll try to define and decide on something sensible here
那样的话，一切都会变得非常干净，非常容易，而且会很好地运行
and then that way, everything will be just kind of really clean and really easy, and will really work well
但我们也不必以简单的方式结束这一切
but we don't have to end it all literally simple probably as well
因为同一功能没有1000个不同的代码部分，这取决于你们想怎么做，对吧
because there's not like 1000 different code parts for the same thing, depending on how you want to do this or that, right
我不喜欢那样，我知道这对Hazel不太好，所以那就是为什么我想以某种方式做这件事
I don't like that, it's not going to work out well for Hazel, I know it, so that's why I want to do this in a certain way
在这种情况下，我想也许我们只是说，Hazel将建立一个静态库，它将简化很多事情
and in this case, I'm thinking maybe we just say, Hazel's gonna build a static library, it's gonna simplify so many things
这意味着，是的，一切都是在构建时进行的，但那很好，因为事情是
it's gonna mean that, yes, everything is kind of at build time, but that's fine, because the thing is um
如果你们把Hazel看作是软件的一种模型，那么就没有理由让它热加载
there's no reason really to have Hazel hot-swap, if you look at like it's software's kind of model
他们在很多游戏中都是这样做的，比如《末日》，在那里他们至少有三个，在那里他们有
that they do for a lot of games like doom, where they kind of old them three at least, where they had
他们在大多数引擎游戏中都是这样做的，但他们的游戏实际上是作为dll构建的
and they do it for most of their engine games, but they have the game actually being built as a dll
然后引擎加载dll，那就是你们的游戏，非常有用，非常好，因为意味着你们的处理方法
and then the engine loads that dll, and that's your game, that's really useful, and that's really nice, because it means that your deal
你们知道游戏是一个dll文件，就可以使用它进行热加载，并可以随心所欲地使用它
you know the game is a dll file, which you're gonna get riot and hot-swap and do whatever you want with
然后是引擎处理，比如为什么你们希望引擎可以热加载
and then the engine deal, like why would you want the engine to be hot-swap
这没有任何意义，因为理想情况下，你们使用这个引擎来制作游戏或应用程序
that doesn't make any sense, because ideally you're using this engine to make a game or an application
所以引擎已经完成，引擎已经准备好，你们不只是一直在修改引擎代码
so the engine's done, the engine's ready, you're not just modifying engine code all time
你们在修改什么游戏代码或应用程序代码，那是你们需要热加载的部分
what are you modifying your game code or your application code, that's the part that you want a hot-swap
因此这种设计无论如何都不是真正有益的，它只对引擎开发有益，而不是对使用引擎有益
so this design is not really beneficial anyway, it's only beneficial for engine development, not for actually using the engine
这就是我们想长期考虑的，显然那是一种长期战略
which is what we want to think about long term, obviously that's like a long term kind of strategy
所以那也是我认为很重要的一点，然后另一件事是我们要有脚本，我们要百分之百地有脚本
so that's an important point I think as well, then the other thing is that we're gonna have scripting, we have 100% gonna have scripting
这是不可能的，这个引擎不会有脚本，不是所有都是C++，对吧
this is no way, this engine's not gonna have scripting, it's not gonna be in C++ as well as everything, right
因此，很明显，脚本将是实时可编辑和实时热加载的
so because of that, obviously the scripts are gonna be live live editable and live hot-swap easy
好吧，那很好，那意味着，这种C++代码
right, that's fine, that's implied, this kind of stuff C++ code
我认为我们不应该做任何努力来确保这是热加载的
I don't think we should put any effort into making sure, that's hot-swap
因为这是不必要的，所以那是一种想法，我还想说什么，是的，这将解决很多错误
because it's just not necessary, so that's kind of the idea, what else did I want to say, yeah so it's going to solve a lot of errors
这意味着我们不必处理dll边界问题或安全库的不同版本
it's going to mean that we don't have to deal with dll boundary issues or different versions of the safe possible library
可能会导致非常恼人的错误，这意味着我们不必导出或导入东西
potentially causing really annoying errors, it means that we don't have to export or import things
我不知道，设置一个热加载库确实能更好的运行，因为它们只是在运行
I don't know, set a hot-swap just really nice to work with, because they're just work
对吧，它们只包含所需的符号，然后在最后，将其添加到exe文件中，并添加到最终产品中
right, they only contain the symbols they need, and then at the end, add into the exe file into your actual final product
那就是一切都被拉入和链接的地方，这也让你们在运行时获得更快的性能
that's where everything gets pulled in and linked, which gives you just faster performance at runtime as well
因此，我现在很难做到这一点，考虑了几个星期后，我真的很难证明实际使用dll是合理的
so it's hard to kind of for me right now, having thought about this for several weeks, it's really hard for me to justify actually using dlls
例如，假设我们有一个用C#编写的级别编辑器，它是用WPF之类编写的
if we had like a level editor that was written in C#, for example hypothetically, and that was written in WPF or something like that
是的，我们可能不得不使用dll，这是没有办法的，但我没有这个计划
yeah we'd probably we would have to use a dll, there's no way around that, but I have no plans for that
正如我所说的，关卡编辑器和游戏引擎工具都是原生编写的，对吧，在这个阶段使用ImGui
as I said the level editor and all the game engine tools are going to be written natively, right, using ImGui at this stage
虽然我们使用什么ui系统并不重要，但关键是它们本质上是作为游戏编写的，对吧
although it doesn't matter what ui system we use, the point is they're going to be written as games essentially, right
它们将被编写为实时运行时应用程序，这也是最好的
they're going to be written as real time runtime applications, which is going to be again the best
在我的情况下，快速方式就像是编写这些工具的最快方式，因为我没有团队
and fast way like the fastest way to actually write these tools, in my situation, because I don't have a team
那还将带来跨平台的额外好处
and that's also gonna have the added benefit of being cross platform
没错，WPF是跨平台的，仅限windows，显然可以使用Qt，但没有办法，老实说，我想用Qt
right, the WPF is in cross platform is windows only, obviously we could use Qt, but there's no way, I want to use Qt to be honest
我们可以写所有的东西，比如ImGui，都是运行时，都准备好在所有平台上运行
we can write everything, ImGui everything's runtime, everything's kind of ready to go on all platforms
包括像外国或我们选择在Hazel支持的任何东西，我认为这肯定是最好的策略
including like foreigns or whatever we choose to support in Hazel, I think it's gonna be the best strategy for sure
我们当然不需要dll来真正运行，我们只需要静态库就可以了
and we definitely don't need a dll for that to actually work, we just need like static libraries will be fine
事实上，就我所知，更好的是，那就是我的计划，希望你们能参与进来
and in fact even better, as far as I can see, so that's my plan, hopefully you guys can get on board um with that
但是让我知道我是什么意思如果我，如果我错过了一些非常重要的事情，我会有一点压力
but let me know what like I mean if I, if I'm missing something really big, I'm getting a little stress
我可能会挤一下，嗯，如果你们有什么，如果我错过了什么大事，或者你们这么认为
I might just give this a squeeze, um if you guys have anything, if I've missed something big or you guys think that
等等，你们在做什么，为什么你们的dll更好，这样做，在下面留下评论，对吧，这是讨论
whoa hang on what are you doing why are you dlls are better, you know, do that, leave a comment below, right, this is a discussion
我真的很想听听你们对我们应该做什么的看法
and I really want to hear your opinion on what we actually should do
但是如果我们决定使用静态库，我认为我们应该
but if we do decide to go with static libraries, which I think we should
我们可能应该在下一期中完成，喜欢这个声音吗？我们肯定应该在下一期中完成
we should probably get that done in the next episode, you like that sound, we should definitely do that in the next episode
因为如果我们能够完成这些工作，我们将创建许多不同的接口类和类似的东西来进行渲染
because if we can get that stuff done, we're about to make a lot of different api classes and stuff like that for rendering
因此，如果我们选择使用静态库的话，我们就可以完全摆脱Hazel API，而不必使用任何东西
so instead of having to sprinkle everything with Hazel API, we can get rid of that entirely, if we choose to go with the static library thing
所以我们可能会在下一期播出，所以我会等几天再播出下一期，看看你们对此的反应
so we'll probably do that next episode, so I'll wait a few days before I make the next episode, just to see your response to this
但我想这就是我们要去的方向，然后在那之后的一期，我想我们要从渲染器开始
but I think that's the direction we're gonna go in, and then the episode after that, we're gonna I guess start on the renderer
如果你们对模块定义文件感兴趣的话，我可以做一个
and kind of deal with that, so and then I might make a, if you guys are interested in that module definition file
我想我可能会在未来制作，我已经写下来了，我会制作一个综合系列视频，涵盖那个
I think I might make in the future, I've already written it down, I will make a syposized series video which covers that
然后你们可以走那条路线，如果你们选择的话，无论如何，很抱歉这次我们没有进行渲染
and then you can kind of go that route personally if you kind of choose to, anyway, sorry that we didn't get to rendering this time
但我很高兴我们讨论了这件事，因为事实上，如果我们跳到这里
but I'm glad that we talked about this stuff, because like in fact, if we just jump in here
因为我甚至没有解决所有问题，如果在这里停一下，然后看看，你们知道，再也没有错误了
cause I didn't even address everything, if we jump in here for a second, then we take a look at, you know, we got no errors anymore
因为只是一些烦人的警告，对吧，一半是因为dll问题，一半是因为看出来
because some of annoy warnings, right, half this stuff is because of dll issues, half this stuff like see out
就像你们知道的那样，这些东西不安全是因为用了弃用函数，但这不是我们的，这是ImGui
like you know this stuff being unsafe is because we were using deprecative functions, but again, this isn't us, it's ImGui
我可能会使用sscanf_s，它只为你们搜索的缓冲区提供一个大小
I will probably use s scan s s scan f on the score s, which just provides a size for the buffer you're scouting into
只是为了避免溢出，那是一件非常容易的事情，但由于这不是我的代码，要做的就是构建
just so that you don't overflow it, and that's a really easy thing to do, but again since that's not my code what we'll do is just build
ImGui或构建任何我们需要的库就在premake文件中定义_CRT_SECURE_NO_WARNINGS
ImGui or build whatever we need with this _CRT_SECURE_NO_WARNINGS defined in the premake file
dll的东西，然后这些东西就是，在premake文件中，不应该在premake文件中
dll stuff, and then this stuff is just stuff, that's in the premake file, that should not be in the premake file
所以我们有很多重要的事要做，因为我两周后就要结婚了，我忙得不可开交
so there's a lot of major and stuff that we will do, and potentially again, because I am getting married in two weeks, and I am crazy busy
因为我仍然在全职工作，虽然我也在婚礼前一周休息了，就像你们知道的
because I'm still working full time, although I did take the week before the wedding off as well, just like you know
回到现实中来，不要到处乱跑，为我的婚礼感到压力
just come back into reality, and just not be running around everywhere, and be stressed from my wedding
因为婚礼现在一切都在进行
because of the wedding, and everything is going on right now
我想也许我们可以放轻松，那样的话，我仍然可以每周给你们一期
I think that maybe we can just take it easy, and that way, I could still give you guys an episode every week
但它可能有点温和，我们可能会花点时间来清理东西
but it might be a little bit tamer, and we might just take this time to just clean stuff up
说到这里，就像我已经准备好录制渲染那期一样，我想进行渲染
with that being said, like I'm ready to make the rendering episodes as well, I want to make the rendering
我们要做的第一件事，我今天早上刚制定了一个计划，我们要做的是，我们要开始创造
the first thing we'll do, I kind of just made a plan this morning is what we're going to do is, we're going to start off way creating
就像OpenGL的渲染上下文和交换链一样，对吧，最后很明显，当我们支持其他接口时
like a rendering context and swap chain kind of for OpenGL, right, and eventually obviously when we support other apis
它们也会有这些类，所以一旦我们有了这些类，我们就可以继续创建
they will have those classes as well, so once we have that, we can probably move on to creating
我想从创建一个非常基本的着色器编译文件开始，这样我们就可以很容易地创建着色器
I want to probably start off with creating a very basic shader compilation file, just so we can really easily just create shaders
因为那很重要，这样我们在制作东西的时候，仍然可以在屏幕上看到东西
because that's gonna be important, and then that way as we build stuff, we'll still be able to have stuff on the screen
因为我们总是可以在需要的时候编写OpenGL客户端，然后
because we can always write our OpenGL clients side, when we need to right, and then we'll kind of just
你们知道，这样我们每期都会在屏幕上显示一些东西，这不像嘿，这里有五期渲染的东西
you know, that way we have something on the screen every episode, it's not like hey, here's five episodes of rendering stuff
最后，我们会看到一个三角形，没有原因，通常是这样的，我们总是会看到一个三角形
and then at the end, we'll see a triangle, no cause, that's kind of how it usually goes, we'll always see a triangle
然后，我们会慢慢地将这些代码抽到类中，然后类似地抽到实际的渲染接口和渲染中
and then we'll kind of slowly pull that code away into classes and into like into our actual rendering api and into our render
所以那就是我的计划
so that's my plan with that
希望你们喜欢这个视频，如果喜欢的话，就为它点赞吧，让我知道你们对这一切的想法
hope you guys enjoyed this video, if you did, you can hit the like button, let me know your thoughts about all this
再说一次，你们知道，老实说，我真的很沮丧，没有继续构建这个渲染器
again, you know, it's really frustrating for me to be honest to just not kind of move on and build this renderer
但你们必须明白我现在正经历着人生的一段时期
but again like you have to understand I'm going through a period of my life right now
在那里，我不能像我想做的那样多而不发疯，所以我宁愿像另一个月一样抵消这一点
where I just cannot like just do as much as I want to without going insane,so I would rather just offset this like another month essentially
或者就像你们所知道的那样，下个月再做，然后在一切都安定下来后再努力搞
or just like just kind of you know, again be a bit cruzy over this next month, and then hit it hard after everything settles down
那就是我们要做的，我想那会比现在全力以赴投降要好得多
and just that's when we'll do it, and I think that'll be a lot better than just kind of going full spit ahead and surrendering right now
然后不得不休息一下，因为很明显我要离开了，我就像度蜜月一样
and then having to take a break, because obviously I will be going away I'm like a honeymoon and all of that stuff
所以你们还可以帮助支持patreon.com/thecherno，非常感谢所有使本系列成为可能的人
so yes, you also have to help support series on patreon.com/thecherno, huge thank you to everyone who makes this series possible
如果你们不能等完成这些清理，并且你们想尽快得到这些东西，请支持我在patreon上的工作
if you can't wait for me to do all this cleanup code, and you want to just get this stuff as soon as possible support me on patreon
你们可以访问Hazel开发分支的github存储库，它已经有了类似OpenGL的渲染器
you'll get access to the github repository for the development branch of Hazel, which already has like an OpenGL renderer written basically
它没有那么完整，你们不会看到像pbr阴影一样的，但它要成熟得多
it's not like complete, you're not going to see like pbr shading yet, but it is a lot more mature
有一个渲染器指令队列，它将所有希望代码渲染指令的内容写入指令缓冲区
there's like a renderer command queue, that's written everything wishing codes rendering commands into like a command buffer
然后在另一个线程上执行它们，所有这些东西都已经存在了
and then executes them to actually on a different thread, all that kind of stuff is already there
如果你们迫不及待地想看看，否则，嗯，看看你们能做多少
so if you can't wait check that out, otherwise um see how much you can do
我想这是你们自己的，所有这些我提到的清理引用
I guess of this by yourself all this cleanup quote that I've mentioned
对于你们来说，一个非常好的家庭任务就是把Hazel转化为静态库
a really good kind of home web task for you guys can vert Hazel into a static library
看看看看你们是怎么做的，因为有一些小事情你们必须调整
see how you, see how you go with that, because there are a few kind of little small things that you will have to tweak
看看你们能不能得到零警告的Hazel，这是你们的挑战，下次见，再见
and see if you can get Hazel building with zero warnings, that's your challenge, I will see you next time, goodbye